<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding on CB</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coding on CB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>cborendev@gmail.com (Cole Boren)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>cborendev@gmail.com (Cole Boren)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Cole Boren (CC BY 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Origin Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/9-10-24-origin-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>cborendev@gmail.com (Cole Boren)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/9-10-24-origin-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-geology--naval-warfare-maps-to-go-developer&#34;&gt;From Geology &amp;amp; Naval Warfare Maps to Go Developer&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Cole. My programming journey began in late 2019, but my path there was anything but direct. After studying Geology in college and working as a Field Geologist for about a year, I found myself creating maps for naval warfare ships at the US DOD. It was there that I first dipped my toes into bash scripting to automate my workflow, and I was instantly hooked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2 id="from-geology--naval-warfare-maps-to-go-developer">From Geology &amp; Naval Warfare Maps to Go Developer</h2>
<p>Hi, I&rsquo;m Cole. My programming journey began in late 2019, but my path there was anything but direct. After studying Geology in college and working as a Field Geologist for about a year, I found myself creating maps for naval warfare ships at the US DOD. It was there that I first dipped my toes into bash scripting to automate my workflow, and I was instantly hooked.</p>
<p>When 2020 rolled around, like many others with extra time on their hands, I dove deeper into programming. What fascinated me most was the democratization of the field - anyone willing to put in the time and effort could become a programmer, regardless of their background. This realization was particularly exciting for someone like me, coming from a non-traditional tech background. I started with basic C programming, creating simple programs like &ldquo;Hello World&rdquo; and a basic calculator. Initially, I thought I wanted to be a &lsquo;frontend developer&rsquo;, so I also dabbled in HTML and CSS. Little did I know that this curiosity would lead me on a journey from geology and naval warfare maps to becoming a Go developer.</p>
<p>A turning point came when I read an article about a former geologist who transitioned into programming. I reached out to him (thanks, Adam!) and our chat about geology, programming, and the tech lifestyle convinced me to take the plunge. I quit my job and committed to becoming a work-from-home dev. The challenge of programming, the flexibility of remote work, and the potential earnings were too tempting to resist. I moved back home and enrolled in a course with <a href="https://www.tech901.org/">Tech901</a>, where I learned the basics of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Shortly after, <a href="https://cooksys.com/">Cook Systems</a> reached out and put me through an intensive bootcamp focused on Java and Spring Boot. Almost immediately, I landed a job as a Backend Developer (not frontend, ironically) at FedEx through Cook. Despite feeling underprepared as do most early career devs, I embraced the challenge and learned rapidly. After a year, I felt I had truly cut my teeth in programming professionally, then my career took another turn.</p>
<p>A company called Green Mountain (formerly Green Mountain Technology) &lsquo;GM&rsquo; contacted me about a frontend position. Although I ended up in a backend role with C#/.NET, my time at GM was transformative. I learned about software engineering, unit testing, performance optimization, SQL, Kafka, APIs, architecture, code reviews, mentoring/how to mentor others, and project ownership. The experience and mentorship I received at GM were invaluable, its what helped my find my love for backend programming. However, like many tech companies in 2022-2023, GM faced layoffs. After about two years with GM, I decided it was time to spread my wings further. This led me to Hone Health, a fast-paced telehealth startup where I&rsquo;ve been for about a year. At Hone, I&rsquo;ve worn many hats - from helpdesk to bug hunting, infrastructure work to feature development, you name it and I&rsquo;ve done it. As I write this, I&rsquo;m transitioning to a new role as a Go developer - an exciting new chapter in my career. This journey from naval warfare maps to Go development has been filled with challenges, growth, and unexpected turns. I&rsquo;m looking forward to sharing more about my ongoing learning and experiences in future blog posts.</p>
<p>~ Stay tuned as I continue to document my adventures in software development, and hopefully improve my writing along the way! 😆</p>
<hr>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
